<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Organic Protein Reviews</title>
    <description>Finding the best organic supplements</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 07:35:56 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 07:35:56 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cocoa Powder and Unflavored Organic Protein</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Unflavored organic protein poweder shakes are some of the most pure, natural sources for the protein you need. I like to make a post-workout shake, for example, with only two ingredients:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Organic, grass-fed whey powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Organic, grass-fed milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t get much simpler than that! I like knowing that my post-workout nutrition contains only the natural ingredients I want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what about flavor? To me, the above (organic whey protein + organic milk) tastes like “thick milk”, which is to say that it tastes the same way plain milk tastes, but more so. Maybe the right analogy is that the shake flavor is to milk what mango nectar is to mango juice; it’s just a more intense version of the same flavor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like that taste, but sometimes I want to drink an organic protein shake with a different flavor. My go-to ingredient for that is raw cacao; specifically, I like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Healthworks-Certified-Organic-Cacao-Powder/dp/B00EKLPLU4&quot;&gt;Healthworks Cacao Powder&lt;/a&gt;, which is a USDA certified organic raw cacao powder. In fact, the only ingredient is raw cacao! It blends well, so I just put a small scoop of it in a shaker bottle with my organic whey and my organic milk. It tastes great! I’d describe it as tasting like chocolate milk without the sugar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, the powder is completely sugar free. I use about a tablespoon per shake, so the total nutritional footprint of the powder is negligible: Less than a gram of fat, and about 3.6 grams of carbs. The serving size on the packages is 2.5 tbsp with 32 servings per container; since I only use about 1 tbsp, though, I get 80 servings per container. That’s really what I’d recommend: More than a tablespoon, and the cocoa flavor becomes really powerful, almost overwhelming!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you like organic protein shakes but want to add a natural flavor, try cacao powder; I think it’s a great alternative to “plain milk” tasting shakes!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/cocoa-powder.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/cocoa-powder.html</guid>
        
        <category>Organic Whey</category>
        
        <category>Organic Casein</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Comparing Unflavored Protein Powders</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of unflavored natural and/or organic protein powders out there. In this blog post, we compare five of the top protein powders; we’ll look at the economics (cost per gram of protein) as well as the sourcing and processing information. It’s surprising how much both cost, source, and processing vary!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a table summarizing the data. Prices come from Amazon as of 3 April 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Naked Whey, 5lb Bulk&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Promix Whey, 5lb Bulk&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Source Classic Organic Whey, 2lbs&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Raw Organic Whey, 12oz&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Now Foods Organic Whey Protein, 1lb&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Serving Size (grams)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;30&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;30&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;25&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;25&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;24&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protein (grams)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;25&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;25&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;21&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;19&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servings Per Container&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;76&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;76&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;36&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;19&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost Per Container&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$89.99&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$79.99&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$64.99&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$35&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$25.06&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost Per 100 Grams of Protein&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$4.74&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$4.21&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$8.60&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$12.50&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$6.94&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protein Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;whey protein concentrate&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;whey protein concentrate&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;whey protein concentrate&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;whey protein concentrate&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;whey protein concentrate&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In putting together this grid, one thing that really surprised me was how much variability there is in cost. I mean, $12.50 versus $4.21?! That’s huge. The cost difference seems to mostly be explained by package size; five pound bulk containers are much cheaper than one pound or less containers. Hopefully Source, Raw, and Now will release bulk cannisters of their proteins in the future!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As readers of this blog will know, one of my favorite protein powders is Naked Whey, which I think is a insanely high-quality protein source. Based on the chart above, I may start trying Promix as well. Of course, the sourcing and proceessing of each protein source also matters. Here’s what each company has to say about its protein:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Naked Whey&lt;/em&gt;: Only One Ingredient: 100% Grass Fed Pure Whey Protein with zero additives. Naked Whey no artificial sweeteners, flavors, or colors and is GMO-Free, Growth Hormone Free, Soy Free and Gluten-Free. All Natural Whey: Our Grass Fed Whey is sourced from small dairy farms in California to bring you a non-denatured whey packed full of essential amino acids, clean protein and glutathione. Cold Processed: Unlike most whey protein powders, Naked Whey is cold processed to ensure zero contamination from chemical detergents (no acid or bleach), synthetic additives, or heavy metals, and this maintains important naturally occurring growth factors.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Promix&lt;/em&gt;: ProMix works directly with farms to always give you the best quality and price. 3rd Party Lab Tested for Heavy Metals. Soy-free, Gluten-Free, Nut-free, Acid and Bleach-free, Cold-processed Microfiltration. ProMix Whey comes from the milk of grass-fed cows.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source&lt;/em&gt;: Non-GMO Project Verified, American Humane Association Certified, USDA Organic, Kosher Organic Whey Protein. Pure organic whey from the milk of grass-fed cows from family farms in Northern California Soy-free, Gluten-free, processed without acid or bleach, rBGH/rBST hormone free, non-denatured, cold-processed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Raw&lt;/em&gt;: Only 1 Ingredient: 100% Pure organic whey protein from the milk of grass-fed jersey cows that graze on open pastures over 300 days a year. GMO Free, Soy Free, rBGH/rBST hormone free, Gluten Free, Corn Free, Grass-Fed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Now Foods&lt;/em&gt;: Free of rbgh and antibiotics. All natural - no aspartame, no sucralose, no acesulfame-k.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, the most important things to look at when choosing a whey protein powder are:
1. What are the ingredients other than whey?
2. Am I getting whey protein concenrate or whey protein isolate? (See this post on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.builtlean.com/2013/05/14/whey-concentrate-vs-isolate-whats-the-difference/&quot;&gt;BuiltLean&lt;/a&gt; for an explanation of the difference.)
3. What is the quality of the milk source and how is it processed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the above products are whey protein concentrate, and all of them have at most one other ingredient. (Promix, Source, and Now include sunflower lecithin (a natural emulsifier that keeps protein shakes from ‘clumping’); Naked and Raw have no ingredients other than whey.) So, for me, the only remaining factor to consider is the quality of the milk used to make the whey, and the way in which the product is processed. Luckily, most of the protein products above are stellar in this
regard! Here’s my summary. A question mark means “unknown”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Grass-Fed Cows?&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Growth Hormone Free?&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Cold-Processed?&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;USDA Organic?&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Naked&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Yes!&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Yes!&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Yes!&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Promix&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Yes!&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Yes!&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Yes!&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Source&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Yes!&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Yes!&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Yes!&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Yes!&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Raw&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Yes!&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Yes!&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Yes!&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Now Foods&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Yes!&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I had to declare a winner, I’d say that Source ekes out a win over the others – but really, all of the products above seem great to me, and much better than the protein powders I was using just a couple years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a final thought, one thing I really like about Promix and Source is that their products are independently tested for heavy metal content. Heavy metals, such as lead and mercury, are present in many of our foods, but are unhealthy in any quantity; Promix and Source have third-party labs test their products. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://source-organic.com/pages/third-party-verified&quot;&gt;Source’s page&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://promixnutrition.com/pages/independent-lab-test-results&quot;&gt;Promix’s&lt;/a&gt;.) Both of their
products are well under the USP Standard limits, which is great! This makes me feel even better about their protein powders, and I’d love to see similar reports from the other companies above.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/unflavored-grid.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/unflavored-grid.html</guid>
        
        <category>Organic Whey</category>
        
        <category>Organic Casein</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Guide for new posts</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;required&quot;&gt;Required&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;categories&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;categories&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;IF&lt;/em&gt; it’s a post, the categories array is required with at least
&lt;em&gt;the first element&lt;/em&gt; set to the permalink name of its parent page
(so that breadcrumbs work).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;categories&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;topics ...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two top-level categories with provided index pages are &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;topics&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;works&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advanced:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;nobullet&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The following settings will list the first topic in the subcategory
in the topics index and (soon) will create back/next links within the
subcategory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;nobullet&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To start, create a first post for the sub-category, but with a permalink.
The category list can be space-delimited on one line or in a bulleted list.
Note that the category names must exactly match the permalink.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;categories&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;topics my-great-vacation&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;permalink&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;/topics/my-great-vacation/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;nobullet&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The site permalink would be:
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/topics/my-great-vacation/index.html&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;nobullet&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For topics within that sub-category, add the additional category and no
permalink:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;categories&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;topics my-great-vacation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;nobullet&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;resulting in: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/topics/my-great-vacation/topic-title.html&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;nobullet&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(coming soon) This creates back and next links.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;excerpt&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;excerpt&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll wanna provide an excerpt in front-matter, because relying on jekyll to
get the excerpt from the body has too many caveats. The excerpt is truncated
as necessary in references, so it can be as long as you want. But, it’s also
displayed, centered, right under the topic title (in all caps).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;excerpt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;yada yada&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;permalink&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;permalink&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;IF&lt;/em&gt; it’s a parent page, use a permalink for it’s new category, but don’t specify
that new category for this parent page itself, because it becomes the index
that a breadcrumb link would pop up to, ie: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/new-category/index.html&lt;/code&gt;. Also see
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;categories&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;permalink&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;/new-category/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;title&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Title for &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;title/&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;h1/&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. For this and all other fields refer to Yaml
restrictions on when you need to quote the value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;My interesting topic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;presentation-options&quot;&gt;Presentation options&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;author&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;author&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want the article to be attributed to an author, specify a name that
corresponds to a key in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_data\authors.yml&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;author&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;key_name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;background-image&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;background-image&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want a larger title block with a background image, specify it here.
If it’s in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/images/&lt;/code&gt; folder, specify just the name;
otherwise specify the folder relative to your jekyll root, starting with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/&lt;/code&gt;.
If it’s a remote image, begin the name with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;//&lt;/code&gt;.
Use a high resolution image, if possible,
for when viewed full screen. Once displayed, you’ll wanna slowly resize your
browser or use its developer tools to see how the image responds for all &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@media&lt;/code&gt;
breakpoints and crop it as necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;background-image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;imagefile.png&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;icon&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;icon&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the featured articles on the main page, if you want an icon other than
the heart icon, specify the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;font-awesome&lt;/code&gt; icon identifier (just the text after &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;fa-&lt;/code&gt;).
See the &lt;a href=&quot;/topics/icons.html&quot;&gt;font-awesome icons&lt;/a&gt;
topic for a list of available icons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;icon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;industry&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;layout&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;layout&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For both posts and pages, there’s no need to specify the layout.
Specifying the layout is optional because defaults
are set in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_config.yml&lt;/code&gt; file to set the layout based on the folder it’s in
(&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_pages&lt;/code&gt;). The layout &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; useful for pages outside of these folders,
however.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;layout&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;page|post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;options&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;options&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The options allow you to customize the page somewhat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;options&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;minihead&lt;/span&gt;      &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# as minimal a title as possible, and no date printed&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;fullwidth&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# leaving only a tiny margin on all media sizes&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;nocomment&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# disable disqus comments for this post&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;nomenu&lt;/span&gt;        &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# for pages, don&#39;t add to the menu&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;nolanding&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# for pages and featured posts, don&#39;t add to the landing page&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that disqus comments are not displayed on &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;works&lt;/code&gt; posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ordering-and-site-map-options&quot;&gt;Ordering and site map options&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;changefreq&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;changefreq&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The default change frequency for all pages in the site map is &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;monthly&lt;/code&gt;.
Depending on how often you think you’ll edit a page, you can set the page
change frequency. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.v9seo.com/blog/2011/12/27/sitemap-xml-why-changefreq-priority-are-important/&quot;&gt;Here’s a good guide&lt;/a&gt; on when to use the available values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;changefreq&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;weekly&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;key&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;key&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All files in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_pages&lt;/code&gt; folder are displayed in the nav menu unless you
set the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nomenu&lt;/code&gt; option.
Use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;key&lt;/code&gt; to specify the order you want the pages listed in the nav menu.
Values are sorted in ascending order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;key&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lastmod-date&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lastmod&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;date&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want the site map &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lastmod&lt;/code&gt; setting to be updated, you can set one or both of
these to your new modified date as &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD HH:MM:SS +/-TTTT&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lastmod&lt;/code&gt; has priority).
If you use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;date&lt;/code&gt;, the date shown on the page is also modified, overriding the
date in the filename. The timestamp is assumed to be UTC unless you specify the
time zone offset afterward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;lastmod&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;2016-03-13 23:11:00&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;date&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;2016-01-01 00:00:00 -0800&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;priority&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;priority&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;priority&lt;/code&gt; to specify two things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the grouping in the works index&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the site map priority&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;priority&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;0.8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the works index, the works are grouped by priority, listed by descending priority
and by descending date within each priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; For now, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;works&lt;/code&gt; posts &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; have a priority set for the ordering
          to work. If you get a “&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;can&#39;t compare float with nil&lt;/code&gt;” error in your
          jekyll build, there’s a missing priority somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the value is used to set the site map priority,
it must be set to a value between 0 and 1.0.
I have three groups of works, using priorities 0.7, 0.6, and 0.5.
None as high as featured posts, but then, I’m not looking for a job right now. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Default priorities in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sitemap.xml&lt;/code&gt; file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;1.0&lt;/code&gt; - Landing page&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;0.9&lt;/code&gt; - Featured posts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;0.7&lt;/code&gt; - Other posts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;0.5&lt;/code&gt; - Pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sitemapexclude&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sitemap_exclude&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;yes&lt;/code&gt; if you want to exclude a page from the sitemap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;sitemap_exclude&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;yes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tags&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tags&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For &lt;em&gt;topics&lt;/em&gt; posts, the only tag that has an effect right now is &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;featured&lt;/code&gt;,
which adds it to the top of the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/topics/&lt;/code&gt; page. The most recent eight
featured posts are also added to the main landing page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;tags&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;featured&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For &lt;em&gt;works&lt;/em&gt; posts, the tags become a listing of skills demonstrated. For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;tags&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;C&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;Windows DLL&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;SGML&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/skills.png&quot; alt=&quot;web page display of the preceding tags&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can add the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;featured&lt;/code&gt; tag to a work if you want it to appear on the main landing page.
The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;featured&lt;/code&gt; tag is excluded from the list of skills on the page and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;works&lt;/code&gt; index.
However, its page priority overrides the standard priority of featured posts in the site map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;css-and-script-support&quot;&gt;CSS and Script support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;includes&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;includes&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your page needs to include stylesheets or scripts, provide ‘em as either
local or remote URLs. Prefix remote urls with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;//&lt;/code&gt;, not &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;http&lt;/code&gt;. Stylesheets
are included in the header and scripts at the bottom before the body closes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;style-includes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;/local/path/to/stylesheet.css&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;//remote.com/url/to/stylesheet.css&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;script-includes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;/local/path/to/script.js&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;//remote.com/url/to/script.js&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;style-script&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;style, script&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are useful when you want to embed styles and scripts outside of the
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;content&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; area.
Use the yaml &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;|&lt;/code&gt; indented block to ensure line breaks are preserved.
The styles are included in the header below stylesheet includes;
scripts are included at the bottom below script includes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;style&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;/* some css block here */&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;.some-class {&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;somestyle: definition;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;script&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;// some script block here...&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;$(document).ready(function(){&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/topics/template.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/topics/template.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>topics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fun Fun day</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is friggin crazy if that’s how it is.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2006 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/topics/my-vacation/test-funfun.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/topics/my-vacation/test-funfun.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>topics</category>
        
        <category>my-vacation</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Test Vienna</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Mozart’s home.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2006 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/topics/my-vacation/test-vienna.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/topics/my-vacation/test-vienna.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>topics</category>
        
        <category>my-vacation</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fun!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here we go.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2006 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/topics/my-vacation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/topics/my-vacation/</guid>
        
        
        <category>topics</category>
        
        <category>my-vacation</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project Y</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;results&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;24% increase in M, measured by N&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project Y involved ….&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/works/works-example2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/works/works-example2.html</guid>
        
        <category>This</category>
        
        <category>That</category>
        
        <category>The other</category>
        
        
        <category>works</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Project Z</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;results&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;19% increase in M, measured by N&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project Z involved ….&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2000 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/works/works-example3.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/works/works-example3.html</guid>
        
        <category>This</category>
        
        <category>That</category>
        
        <category>The other</category>
        
        
        <category>works</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
